Guide to the Robert R. Compton Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert R. Compton papers
1947-1984
SC0382
Compton, Robert R.
1.5 Linear feet
Compton earned his A.B. in 1943 and his Ph.D. in physical science in 1949 from Stanford University. He joined the Stanford faculty in the Dept. of Geology in 1949 and was appointed full professor in 1962. His MANUAL OF FIELD GEOLOGY is recognized as the definitive work on this subject.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The papers largely consist of his field notebooks, 1947-49 and 1955-73, some of which contained reading notes and bibliographies. Also included are the typescripts of several chapters from a book on field geology, 1984; and one letter from R. I. Harker. The California notes appear to be research for his Stanford doctorate: PETROLOGY OF THE SOUTHWESTERN PART OF THE BIDWELL BAR (30') QUADRANGLE, CALIFORNIA, (1949). Other geologic areas covered include the Grouse Creek Range in Utah, the Santa Lucia range in California, the Santa Rosa mountains in Nevada, and the British Isles (England, Scotland, Ireland).
Description of the Collection
Compton earned his A.B. in 1943 and his Ph.D. in physical science in 1949 from Stanford University. He joined the Stanford faculty in the Dept. of Geology in 1949 and was appointed full professor in 1962. His MANUAL OF FIELD GEOLOGY is recognized as the definitive work on this subject.
Access Terms
Compton, Robert R.; Stanford University. Department of Geology. Faculty.; Field notes.; Geology--California --Butte County.; Geology--Field work.; Geology--Great Britain.; Geology--Ireland.; Geology--Nevada.; Geology--Research.; Geology--Utah--Grouse Mountains.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Field notes – California, 1947-49 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Field notes – California, 1947-49 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Field notes – California, 1947-49 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - California, analysis (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - California, analysis (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - California, analysis (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - California, analysis (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Field notes – Cone Peak, 1957, (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Field notes – Cone Peak, 1957, (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Field notes – Cone Peak, 1957, (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Field notes – England, Scotland, Ireland (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Field notes – England, Scotland, Ireland (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Field notes – England, Scotland, Ireland (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes – England, Scotland, Ireland (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Field notes – Grouse Creek Range 1966 [Box Elder County, Utah] (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Field notes – Grouse Creek Range 1967-68 (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Field notes – Grouse Creek Range 1968-73 (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Field notes – Santa Lucia range, CA #1 1955-63 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Field notes – Santa Lucia range, CA #1 1963-64 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Field notes – Santa Lucia range, CA #2 1962-64 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Field notes – Santa Lucia range, CA #2 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Santa Lucia analysis (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Santa Lucia analysis (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Santa Lucia analysis (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Field notes – Santa Rosa mountains [Nevada] (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Field notes – Santa Rosa mountains 1952-58 [Nevada] (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Field notes – Santa Rosa mountains 1957-58 [Nevada] (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Field notes – assorted locations (Florida, Texas, New Mexico, Virginia), 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Book typescript, chapter 3, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Book typescript, chapter 7, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Book typescript, chapters 10 and 14, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Book typescript, chapter 15, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letter from R. I. Harker, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)